[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following aspects of Apple Inc. is a form of intellectual property?",
    "a": "its App Store",
    "b": "its trademark on the apple logo",
    "c": "its global reputation",
    "d": "its code base for iOS",
    "e": "its partnership with Chinese factories",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does The Lathe of Heaven enjoy intellectual property protection?",
    "a": "It was registered under the Cole Protocol.",
    "b": "It has an example in the Library of Congress.",
    "c": "It has a patent.",
    "d": "It is covered by the Lausanne Convention.",
    "e": "It is under copyright.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The duration of a utility patent in the United States is CLOSEST to",
    "a": "one decade",
    "b": "four decades",
    "c": "five decades",
    "d": "three decades",
    "e": "two decades",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Intellectual property rights turn",
    "a": "innovations into inventions",
    "b": "non-excludable goods into excludable goods",
    "c": "non-rival goods into rival goods",
    "d": "inventions into products",
    "e": "public domain into private property",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Patents try to strike a balance between",
    "a": "inventors and investors",
    "b": "national interests and global interests",
    "c": "appropriability and social value",
    "d": "time and utility",
    "e": "producer surplus and consumer surplus",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does a patent allow an inventor who is NOT an entrepreneur to appropriate part of an invention's value?",
    "a": "A patent dissuades small firms from asking for intellectual property rights.",
    "b": "A patent protects the inventor from others copying the invention.",
    "c": "A patent provides near-instant access to capital through loans.",
    "d": "A patent allows the inventor to sell the rights to make the invention to a firm or business.",
    "e": "A patent creates a legal mechanism for licensing reverse engineering rights.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following firms is MOST likely to use patents to protect innovations?",
    "a": "nonprofit organization",
    "b": "partnership",
    "c": "technology startup",
    "d": "sole proprietorship",
    "e": "multinational conglomerate",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following potential downsides apply to patent protection EXCEPT",
    "a": "revealing the secrets of an invention",
    "b": "upfront costs to secure a patent",
    "c": "loss of exclusivity through corporate espionage",
    "d": "effort required to find and identify infringers",
    "e": "uncertain outcomes in court",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which historian argued that inventors' use of the scientific method resulted in improved steam engines?",
    "a": "Larry Neal",
    "b": "David Wootton",
    "c": "Robert Fogel",
    "d": "Stanley Reiter",
    "e": "Alfred Conrad",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The development of television based on the discovery of electricity is an example of",
    "a": "negative externality",
    "b": "knowledge spillover",
    "c": "slipstream effect",
    "d": "patent infringement",
    "e": "technical appropriation",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Nordhaus (2004), on average, what percentage of social value of inventions are inventors able to appropriate?",
    "a": "3.3%",
    "b": "4.4%",
    "c": "1.1%",
    "d": "5.5%",
    "e": "2.2%",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "An advantage of non-profit R&D spending is that non-profit organizations need not worry about",
    "a": "ethics",
    "b": "appropriability",
    "c": "prior art",
    "d": "the patent system",
    "e": "costs of investment",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the NSF, how much scientific research in the United States is funded by the federal government and non-profit organizations?",
    "a": "one-half",
    "b": "one-third",
    "c": "one-quarter",
    "d": "one-fifth",
    "e": "two-thirds",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Governments and other non-profit organizations promote R&D through all of the following methods EXCEPT",
    "a": "enforcement of patent systems",
    "b": "scholarships for aspiring scientists",
    "c": "tax breaks on R&D investment",
    "d": "levies on R&D spending",
    "e": "loans to firms engaged in R&D",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do knowledge spillovers complicate a firm's decision to invest in R&D?",
    "a": "Knowledge spillovers make social value easier for inventor-firms to capture.",
    "b": "Knowledge spillovers may lower that firm's projected R&D costs.",
    "c": "Knowledge spillovers provide an edge to government-funded projects.",
    "d": "Knowledge spillovers benefit the firm and rivals equally.",
    "e": "Knowledge spillovers unlock the potential for cheaper iteration.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who teamed with James Watt to sell early steam engines?",
    "a": "Joseph Priestley",
    "b": "Henry Bessemer",
    "c": "Charles Darwin",
    "d": "Isambard Kingdom Brunel",
    "e": "Matthew Boulton",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2017, infections by tropical diseases ran at",
    "a": "one in two people",
    "b": "one in three people",
    "c": "one in six people",
    "d": "one in four people",
    "e": "one in five people",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why has private investment in R&D for tropical disease treatments remained low?",
    "a": "Government spending has crowded out private R&D for tropical disease treatments.",
    "b": "Tropical diseases are less lethal than others.",
    "c": "Tropical diseases mutate too rapidly for R&D cycles.",
    "d": "Tropical diseases largely affect low-income individuals.",
    "e": "Tropical disease treatments would be cheap and offer little profit.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among new medicines licensed worldwide between 1975 and 1997, how many treated tropical diseases?",
    "a": "forty-four",
    "b": "four",
    "c": "fourteen",
    "d": "thirty-four",
    "e": "twenty-four",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group made a 2007 pact with five countries to fund vaccines against pneumococcal infection?",
    "a": "Gates Foundation",
    "b": "Centers for Disease Control",
    "c": "World Health Organization",
    "d": "Lilly Endowment",
    "e": "Ivy League",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the United States, which entity or entities PRIMARILY subsidized COVID-19 vaccines at the height of the pandemic?",
    "a": "cities",
    "b": "pharmaceutical companies",
    "c": "state governments",
    "d": "insurers",
    "e": "the federal government",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following environments is responsible for a greater share of innovation than its population might suggest?",
    "a": "exurban",
    "b": "rural",
    "c": "small-town",
    "d": "urban",
    "e": "suburban",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "When patents refer to previous patents through citations, we see an example of",
    "a": "appropriability",
    "b": "negative externality",
    "c": "intellectual property",
    "d": "enrichment",
    "e": "knowledge spillover",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following benefits is NOT an aspect of the agglomeration benefit?",
    "a": "lower taxes",
    "b": "networking opportunities",
    "c": "concentration of talent",
    "d": "presence of potential investors",
    "e": "higher wages",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following twentieth century economies would LEAST likely allow an inventor to appropriate value from an invention through markets?",
    "a": "Japan, 1980s",
    "b": "United Kingdom, 1970s",
    "c": "United States, 1950s",
    "d": "Soviet Union, 1960s",
    "e": "Australia, 1990s",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Edmond Albius never appropriate value from his invention?",
    "a": "Being enslaved, he had no way to exercise any property rights.",
    "b": "He sold his intellectual property rights to buy freedom.",
    "c": "No one had any property rights under the command economy in which he lived.",
    "d": "His invention was only publicized after his death.",
    "e": "His invention saw the most use in nations not recognizing his patent.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following entities are examples of economic institutions EXCEPT",
    "a": "market economy structure",
    "b": "democratic government",
    "c": "courts of law",
    "d": "patent systems",
    "e": "manufacturing firms",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "An absolute monarchy is an example of a(n)",
    "a": "extractive institution",
    "b": "liminal institution",
    "c": "autonomic institution",
    "d": "inclusive institution",
    "e": "rival institution",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following economic historians claimed that the concepts of progress and growth were key instigators of the Great Enrichment?",
    "a": "Joseph Schumpeter",
    "b": "Robert Solow",
    "c": "Deirdre McCloskey",
    "d": "Joel Mokyr",
    "e": "Paul Romer",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Established firms may attempt to suppress new inventions because they fear",
    "a": "creative destruction",
    "b": "legal battles",
    "c": "unapproved usage",
    "d": "monopolistic activity",
    "e": "government scrutiny",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  }
]

